<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="7592DFEB-C365-4333-98E7-CC9AEE606D19">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20151002" date="2015-10-02 13:13:18 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Architecture and Beauty,  Conversations with Architects about a Troubled Relationship, 2010&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, 24 January 2010&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Yael Reisner with Fleur Watson, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Architecture and Beauty, Conversations with Architects about A Troubled Relationship&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, Wiley, 2010&#xD;&#xD;About the book&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;What makes the world&#x2019;s top architects tick? Through discussions with 16 leading architects, including Frank Gehry, Zaha Hadid, Greg Lynn and Wolf Prix, unrivalled access is provided to the formative experiences, creative processes and motivations of some of the most influential design figures today. Through personal interviews with Yael Reisner, written up by Fleur Watson, the authors capture the voices, thoughts and personalities of their subjects. So rare and intimate are the insights that it is often akin to being a party to the very conversations themselves. The articles bring us up close to these creative minds with such widely differing positions and opinions, each expressing a very different point of view on aesthetics: whether they think beauty is integral or non-essential to architecture. Fascinating in what it tells us about individual architects and their work, most significantly &lt;i&gt;Architecture and Beauty&lt;/i&gt; raises poignant issues regarding the place of beauty, aesthetics and self-expression within the psychology and the design process of the architectural avant-garde.         &lt;b&gt;Wiley, 2010&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Extracts from the book&#x2019;s introduction &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;- It is important to note that I wrote this book from the perspective of personal impression and based on an understanding of recent architectural events. That is, from the perspective of a designer-architect and not of an architectural historian. &#xD;- In the book, each chapter has many footnotes as well 13-15 images in colour.  &#xD;- This chapter in its full length is illustrated and has 56 footnotes that add further more information. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Genesis of a Troubled Relationship&#xD;Yael Reisner&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&#xD;The genesis of this book&#x2019;s subject matter came as a consequence of a long preoccupation with what I refer to as the &#x2018;troubled relationship&#x2019; between architects and the content of their architecture as well as its relationship with form and aesthetics. Good architecture and brilliant buildings are mostly judged by their capacity to produce an aesthetic experience, yet many outside the architectural profession are surprised to discover that architectural design is neither led nor generated through a process that is engaged with aesthetical issues or visual thinking. Indeed, the diversity of response among these interviewees reveals, in itself, the complexity of this inherently troubled relationship. For many, beauty is a concept that doesn&#x2019;t hold any value within architecture, while for others it has regained its importance and relevance through the framework of a new definition. For example, Frank&#xA0;Gehry sees &#x2018;beauty&#x2019; as something &#x201C;pretty and soft&#x201D; and unconnected with buildings, while Thom Mayne finds the term difficult within itself though defines it as a being &#x201C;compelled&#x201D; to a particular type of architecture. For Gaetano Pesce, beauty is simply perfection, a notion he views as outdated and out of step with the fallible nature of human existence. Paradoxically, beauty can also be the very raison d&#x2019;&#xEA;tre of architecture: For Juhani Pallasmaa it provides the promise of a better human world, while for Odile Decq to be in denial of the importance of beauty is the rejection of a basic human right. Concluding interviewee Hernan Diaz Alonso provides a starkly contemporary viewpoint: For him beauty is integrally embedded within a playful exploration of the grotesque and horrific.&#xD;&#xD;This poignant struggle is also encapsulated in the classic dyad of &#x2018;content and form&#x2019; and how, as a principle, it is understood or perceived by architects of our time. As the Finnish architect Juhani Pallasmaa eloquently describes in his interview: &#x201C;The discipline of architecture is &#x2018;impure&#x2019; in the sense that it fuses utility and poetics, function and image, rationality and metaphysics, technology and art, economy and symbolization. Architecture is a muddle of irreconcilable things and categories.&#x201D; Thus, it seems that the cultural and artistic facet of architecture is often undermined in favour of the more rational, pragmatic requirements of the discipline and, as such, drives this rarely confronted &#x2018;troubled relationship&#x2019;. &#xD;&lt;&lt;&lt; read more &#xD; The &#x2018;hegemony of the eye&#x2019; with its &#x2018;deceits&#x2019; haven&#x2019;t gone well along the content in demand. The expression &#x2018;hegemony of the eye&#x2019; &#x2013; appears during the 20th century as a critic.&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2026;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The historic struggle of the &#x2018;troubled relationship&#x2019; between architectural content and form within the second half of the 20th century resonates with me at a distinctly personal level and has, over time, provided the provocation for my engagement with the notion of the difficult position that beauty holds within architecture. Since my youth I have always admired beautiful objects and adored the look of new things. I believe I was born with a sensitive eye which was developed during my childhood and adolescence despite growing up in the context of the Socialist Modernist and cosmopolitan culture of the provincial city of Tel-Aviv in the 1960s. (The Socialist attitude of Israelis was reinforced by the Jewish iconoclastic tradition.)  In the Israeli collective identity of that time and place was an idealisation of modernity and simplicity, where ideological debates were prevalent and aesthetic &#x2018;indulgence&#x2019; was absent, frowned upon and treated as reminiscent of the old habits of the European Bourgeoisie. I suspect that the Modernist Socialist attitude of the people of Tel-Aviv was the major reason their city&#x2019;s new beauty became diluted and has been badly treated. &#x2018;Content&#x2019; was satisfying and more significant; as Tel-Avivians often remark: &#x201C;We don&#x2019;t argue about taste and smell&#x201D;.&#xD;&#xD;Yet my persistent attitude towards the look of things was mostly triggered by my father - a jolly Austro-Hungarian-Jewish intellectual, a chemical engineer whose heart belonged to European Modernist culture -  who rarely missed an opportunity to tease his daughter for her appreciation of things simply because of their appearance. ( He loved me dearly and put forward his views to &#x2018;rescue&#x2019; me from what he saw as a shallow attitude to life, indulging with silly girlish occupation.) I was accused of adoring empty vessels rather than admiring &#x2018;content&#x2019; produced by intellectual activity, which was, in my father&#x2019;s opinion, worth critically appraising. Our conflict was reinforced daily by a famous Hebrew saying, &#x2018;don&#x2019;t look at the vase but at its content&#x2019;, which finds its parallel in the English saying, &#x2018;don&#x2019;t judge a book by its cover&#x2019; &#x2013; though it doesn&#x2019;t translate directly since within the Hebrew expression we use a word related directly to the word &#x2018;content&#x2019;. &#xD;&#xD;Projecting from my paternal influence, it was my observation that most intellectuals do not have a developed &#x2018;eye&#x2019; with which to truly appreciate the range of values that can be captured within the &#x2018;look of things&#x2019; &#x2013; an observation that seemed underwritten by the context of Socialism. Indeed, they had no genuine interest in looking and set a blind eye to a visual set of references, creating a lack of visual sensibilities over time. I, therefore, assumed that being an intellectual meant the application of the written word through literature and poetry and even theatre to develop a quite different set of sensibilities; it didn&#x2019;t matter if any object was defined by its ugliness, its originality of form, its beauty or its reflection on culture as it would always be reduced to the status of a mere decorative phenomenon. As I began to question this attitude my growing frustration fed my conviction and, in turn, the need for this book. This dialectic informs my research and drives my distrust of the collective message from cultural theory &#x2013; and, more specifically, in architectural discourse &#x2013; that the &#x2018;&lt;i&gt;content&lt;/i&gt;&#x2019;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;of cultural and creative output is more important than its &#x2018;appearance&#x2019;, and that the notion of &#x2018;beauty&#x2019; is often misinterpreted as being devoid of intellectual depth. &#xD;Living in London since the early 1990s I was struck by the disappointing fact that  architecture was predominantly discussed in terms of ethics, content or activity, and much less in terms of its imagery, look, visual values, composition or architectural language. While teaching at The Bartlett I had the opportunity to listen to a large number of lectures given by internationally renowned architects and I couldn&#x2019;t help thinking that the architectural discourse of the time shared attitudes with the arguments I had heard in my youth &#x2013; tragically it seemed to me that many architects had lost their conviction of the cultural importance of aesthetics and its ties with individuality. I hoped to find satisfaction in the shift that &#x2018;digital architecture&#x2019; brought to the international stage, with its focus on form and appearance rather than content. Yet, disappointingly, the digital movement&#x2019;s famous protagonists elevated the status of conceptual objectivity and pursued a &#x2018;rational&#x2019; design process via computational processes. The rise of computer-generated design valued &#x2018;automated&#x2019;, &#x2018;pseudo-scientific&#x2019; and intellectualised characteristics where originality evolved from intrinsic procedures derived from mathematics and not from an individualistic, aesthetic approach.&#xD;&#x2026;&#xD;From a historical perspective, the origins of this troubled relationship throughout the 20th century can be traced to the beginnings of Functionalism where the Modernist ethos was embedded in Socialist ideologies. Since the 1930s architectural discourse has been dogged by the Modernist ambition to avoid being driven by aesthetics and, in turn, the desire not to involve the &#x2018;self&#x2019; or &#x2018;subjectivity&#x2019; during the design process. &#xD;&#x2026;&#xD;As Banham suggests: &#x201C;Nowhere among the major figures of the &#x2019;20s will a pure Functionalist be found.&#x201D; From a contemporary viewpoint, we can conclude that the apologists succeeded in influencing the architectural discourse of the time and pursued an agenda that sidelined aesthetics as a generator for architecture of the 20th century; the generating forces had to be related to the world of utility. &#xD;&#x2026;&#xD;As Colin Rowe confirms, &#x201C;That opposition: &#x2018;objective limits&#x2019; and &#x2018;subjective license&#x2019;, was a crucial component of the architecture thought of the time, and indicated that one is good and the other is highly dubious.&#x201D; &#xD;&#x2026;&#xD;Hence the resistance of Modern architects to embrace a subjective will, or least admit to its role in the creation of their architecture, begins. The popular mantra extracted from the European Functionalist ethos of &#x2018;form follows function&#x2019; clearly reinforces the repression of individualistic expression and the utilitarian facet of Modernism that became the dominant attitude. Surprisingly, as Colin Rowe points out, at the time no-one actually admitted the incompatibility of the two concepts, shifting between an idea of the architect as the servant of technology, the impersonal, and the super important &#x2018;facts&#x2019; and an idea of the architect as the executive of the Zeitgeist, responding to the unconscious demands of the day, interpreting his aesthetic preferences as prophetic intuitions.&#xD;&#xD;The Modernist intellectual attitude is also captured by the well-known British social historian Eric Hobsbawm,  who wrote in the 1990s: &#x201C;Films depended on books from the start&#x2026;&#x201D; (Eric Hobsbawm, &lt;i&gt;Behind the Times, The Decline and Fall of the Twentieth Century Avant Gardes&lt;/i&gt;, Thames and Hudson, 1998.)That is, the underlying message is the most significant value that comes with a film, though he clearly recognises the visual powers and importance of the cinema. In his book &lt;i&gt;Age of Extremes&lt;/i&gt; , in 1994, Hobsbaum expands on his thoughts: &#x201C;One of the most obscure questions in history; and for the historian of culture, one of the most central, is the very phenomenon that brilliant fashion designers, a notoriously non-analytic breed, sometimes succeed in anticipating the shape of things to come better than professional predictors&lt;b&gt;.&#x201D;(&lt;/b&gt; E.H. related his argument to fashion only because it engages with the masses on a fundamental level.) This comment succinctly expresses a refusal to recognise the intellectual depth that can be captured in visual imagery generated intuitively by an individual&#x2019;s insight and a lack of respect for the image unless it carries strong social political content, or a &#x2018;utilitarian task&#x2019;. The intellectualisation of the thought process is prevalent generally in our culture and it has led to further support of the rational faculties as evidenced in architecture&#x2019;s design process. As Walter J. Ong explains, Democracy&#x2019;s &#x2018;public opinion&#x2019; took over individual taste and power. &#xD;&#xD;It took until the late 1970s for emotional content to re-emerge in architecture and for aesthetically driven design to achieve positive status while facilitating the role of the &#x2018;eye&#x2019; once more. This new architectural spirit was led by the dynamic work of Frank Gehry, Zaha Hadid, Coop Himmelb(l)au and Daniel Libeskind and propelled into international prominence by the exhibition &#x2018;Deconstructivist Architecture&#x2019;, curated by Mark Wigley with Philip Johnson at New York&#x2019;s Museum of Modern Art in 1988.  The exhibition&#x2019;s enticing title distracted from the content of the architecture displayed, hijacked the architectural scene and ignited a fire among many architects who must have had an incredible thirst for philosophy or for a cerebral authority rather than for embracing an emotional, authorial voice to lead their architecture.  While resoundingly important and highly successful, the &#x2018;Decon&#x2019; show really indicated the end of a discussion, and, immediately afterwards, the philosophy of Jacques Derrida strengthened as one of the primary authorities in the design process. Thus content became more significant than aesthetics, underpinning a return to the historical architectural tradition of rejecting the &#x2018;self&#x2019;, with all its emotional involvement, as an authority &#xD;&#xD;During the 1990s the use of computers became a prevalent phenomenon in architectural schools and offices and influenced the design process tremendously by enabling more complexity in architectural organisation, three-dimensional forms and structure along with virtual representation and simulations. With this radical shift, the first wave of influential &#x2018;digital architects&#x2019; arrived on the architectural scene &#x2013;&#xA0; such as Greg Lynn, Lars Spuybroek, Marcos Novak, Mark Goulthorpe/dECOi and Mark Burry/SIAL. (&#x2018;Digital architects&#x2019; embrace a complete computational design process using the computer as a design tool from early sketches, developed drawings, drawn models and working drawings through to final products manufactured and produced by rapid prototyping machines) Collectively and individually they took the architectural discourse of the time by storm, drawing on mathematics and the influence of the work of philosopher Gilles Deleuze to provide joint authorities for generating the work and, in turn, swinging the focus back to form and, apparently, back to cerebral aesthetics. However, rationality prevailed and the architect&#x2019;s &#x2018;eye&#x2019; and individuality were removed from the design process, but this time in the name of new objectified computational technologies and production. Content &#x2013; as it was often claimed &#x2013; became fused with form, and form was arrived at through cerebral computational process and technique. &#xD;&#x2026;.&#xD;When embarking on the research material to explore my preoccupation, I felt it was critical to establish direct contact with the architectural elite and chose to interview architects who are or were highly influential among fellow architects and students of architecture &#x2013; usually architects whose work I respect and find attractive, though I do not necessarily agree with their schools of thought. There are sixteen interviewees, who provide a rich cross section of opinion but who don&#x2019;t necessarily represent the widest range of views. Collectively they represent only a small sample of a potentially large number of architects with equally valuable opinions who might have been included. I met most of them two or three times over a span of nearly three years (2004&#x2013;2007). All 16 interviewees are or have been leading architectural educators and are generally considered mavericks who have moved architecture forward through talent, originality, integrity and individuality. In attempting to understand each architect&#x2019;s value system, I drew on my personal experience of struggling with the &#x2018;troubled relationship&#x2019; to get them talk about that subject.. &#xD;&#xD;Frank Gehry exposes the poignancy of self-expression in architecture in democratic societies. Peter Cook hankers for the time in history when architects engaged in passionate battles over their different styles. Eric Owen Moss believes architecture encompasses a colossal breadth of experience in art, history and prosaic pragmatics, and that the expression of these things has built up the integrity of architects as individuals reflecting on their times. Will Alsop argues that individuality is the very thing that architects can offer, believing in the &#x2018;diverse&#x2019; and the &#x2018;speculative&#x2019; and fighting long, arduous battles with British critics and conservatives. Like Odile Decq, Wolf D. Prix vehemently believes that architectural practice shouldn&#x2019;t be separated from architectural theory and research; that architecture functions as both a reflection on architects&#x2019; cultural backgrounds and a general register of culture. For Zvi Hecker, architecture is an expression of the human soul in its ever-changing condition, whereas Juhani Pallasmaa points to the missing presence of the &#x2018;self&#x2019; and believes that architects should rely on personal experience and imagination to fuel their work. For Thom Mayne it is the very uniqueness of architecture that allows it to operate on so many levels &#x2013; conceptual, social, cultural, historical, urbanistic &#x2013; loading multiple perspectives into single frames. Greg Lynn and Mark Goulthorpe claim that content is always fused with form; their interest is focused on form generated by computational processes. Kolatan-MacDonald &#x2013; unlike many of their digital colleagues &#x2013; bravely introduced lateral thinking to the computational process in the mid-1990s, though they still reject any suggestion of Deterministic Formalism. Heranan Diaz Alonso, as the youngest (and final) interviewee, has liberated himself from the cerebral design process and many of the rules of his digital colleagues. &#xD;&#xD;As an architect who has spent years battling with the suppression of the &#x2018;eye&#x2019; and the &#x2018;I&#x2019; and its role in the design process of so many architects, I especially identify with the American psychologist James Hillman who wrote: &#x201C;This curious refusal to admit beauty in psychological discourse occurs even though each of us knows that nothing so affects the soul, so transports it, as moments of beauty &#x2013; in nature, a face, a song, an action or dream.&#x201D; &#xD;9 Bill Beckley with David Shapiro, &lt;i&gt;Uncontrollable Beauty, Towards a New Aesthetics&lt;/i&gt;, Allworth Press, NY, 1998; &#x2018;The Practice of Beauty, an Essay&#x2019;, by James Hillman,) And, as he suggests, &#x201C;We [are] left with fractals and wittily named particles [by definition non-sensate] of theoretical physics,  the puns and parodies of architecture, and the language games of philosophical analysis resulting in a severe dissociation between what is thought, said, and written and what the senses see, the heart feels, and the world suffers.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;More architects should confidently accept the need to generate architecture with an authorial voice, embrace an intuitive eye and lateral thinking, seize impulses and become individualistically speculative. &#xD;&#xD;Beauty as a concept for our age, a work of the individual for other individuals, an authentic product for a pluralistic global time, is not a singular idea. The beautiful is seen by many and is therefore an &#x2018;uncontrollable beauty&#x2019;. (After the inspiring book &lt;i&gt;Uncontrollable Beauty&lt;/i&gt;. Bill Beckley with David Shapiro, &lt;i&gt;Uncontrollable Beauty, Towards a New Aesthetics&lt;/i&gt;, Allworth Press, NY, 1999.)  It is time to argue that architecture&#x2019;s &#x2018;aesthetics&#x2019; have the power to synthesise values, poetics, pragmatic constraints and overbearing cultural issues, and at the same time cohere to the construct of the architectural design. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="24_Architecture_and_Beauty,_Conversations_with_Architects_about_a_Troubled_Relationship,_2010_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="572px" height="72px"/>
</content>
