<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="7592DFEB-C365-4333-98E7-CC9AEE606D19">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20151002" date="2015-10-02 13:13:32 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Forest Project &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;-  a proposal for an installation, outdoors or indoors, April 2015</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>To see the &lt;b&gt;film - &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6i8s7IurYQ8"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Sound track:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Jean Sibelius, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Wood Nymph, Op. 15 &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;- a selected part of it.)&#xD;Melodrama for narrator, piano, two horns and strings&#x2028;&lt;b&gt;Text: Viktor Rydberg&lt;/b&gt;&#x2028;Narrator: Lasse P&#xF6;ysti&#x2028;Piano: Harri Karri&#x2028;Lahti Symphony Orchestra&#x2028;Osmo V&#xE4;nsk&#xE4;, cond.&#x2028;Recording: Church of the Cross (Ristinkirkko), Lahti, Finland, 8-12 January 1996&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#x2028;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;The Forest Project&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Idea&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;A framed long section of pine tree and its roots placed at the Kiasma garden, is the canvas for an epic photography, a mediator and stirrer of ambiguous thoughts and memories from nature, the forest.  Commentating on the importance of nature&#x2019;s presence in urban life, but also on the relevance of roots, past vs. future, and the present life of adaptation, of a sense of belonging; conflicts and vulnerability of identities - individual and collective.&#xD;&#xD;A dual set of epic photography - a scene per each side of the 150 mm thick long wood slab - would be applied by using our proprietary CNC manufacturing script, encoding the photography into the wood by cuttings, embossing, perforating and applying pigments. &#xD;&#xD;Once installed, as the sun moves through the sky the light beams will interact with the imagery, especially the perforated elements portrayed along this kind of scroll that unfold the narrative. Most perforations are angular, thus enabling the light interacting with the images, enhancing a sense of movement, as well as seeing the scenes slightly differently as one walks along the installation, sit in the caf&#xE9;, or take a stroll along the garden paths.&#xD;&#xD;In the winter&#x2019;s shorter days an artificial dynamic interactive light sources (installed as part of the metal holding frame) will be choreographed so as to highlight scenes as people move around.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials and Technology for the work&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;We are a team of two &#x2013; an architect, an a fine art photographer. Each one of us is responsible in this interdisciplinary project for different acts described here: &#xD;&#xD;1.	A pine tree - Pinus Sylvestris - would be selected by the architect, Yael Reisner, and removed with its roots from a forest site, and further cut into two parts (to suits a lorry&#x2019;s length), driven to a woodworking workshop where it would be sliced so as to have its inner long vertical section. That section would be further cut into 5 segments.&#xD;&#xD;These segments&#x2019; heights would vary from 120 cm to 170 cm, (based on the typical height vs. diameter of a pine tree), and all 15 cm thick. They would be held next to each other, building up horizontally the long section of the tree. The roots part would be left three dimensional, and trimmed so as to have smooth edges. &#xD;&#xD;Before the segments would be assembled representing the tree that becomes a scroll unfolding a narrative, there will be another stage taking place &#x2013; described as act 3 below, and to make sense we need to describe act 2 first. &#xD;&#xD;Nevertheless, we would add that this tree-section (25 meters long overall) is held by the specially designed steel frame structure, for a firm hold of the precious object, where the columns are grounded in a slim long concrete slab placed in the garden. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;2.	A dedicated epic photography about the forest, would be done specially by the photographer, Ori Gersht - inspired by folkloric myths while challenging contemporary values.&#xD;&#xD;             The epic photography one sees in our proposal here, is all done by the &#xD;             Gersht in the past. History and metaphor, journeys and geographical   &#xD;             place intertwined with metaphysical space are Gersht concerns, along his&#xD;             highly researched aesthetic.    &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;3.	The epic photography&#x2019;s will be translated by Yael Reisner Studio, from pixels to logarithms and further scripting and encoding, so as to be applied digitally on both sides of the sliced 150 mm thick wood segments/slabs, through perforations, wood cuttings, embossing, and pigmentation, by using a proprietary CNC manufacturing script. The result would be a weather resistant imagery.  &#xD;&#xD;We would have a different narrative on each side of the long tree section, and due to angular perforation, and light interaction, a special effect would be achieved. Thus, for example, as in this sample, when the sun sets, the bird&#x2019;s photos along the forest scene would become more evident as the sunlight shines through the perforation. Due to the angular perforation, as one walks around the wall, the bird would still &#x2018;follow&#x2019; the beholder, from one side to the other, enhancing a sense of movement and continuity, as one can see in the film. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText></richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="17_The_Forest_Project_-_a_proposal_for_an_installation,_April_2015_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="570px" height="84px"/>
</content>
