<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="7592DFEB-C365-4333-98E7-CC9AEE606D19">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20151002" date="2015-10-02 13:13:14 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Dadush Residence, Tel Aviv, 1993 - 1994  &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, 25 January 1994&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>One of the main reasons that the clients liked this overall concept was to do with the fact that each insert - whether it was the sofa as part of the living room, or the extra toilet room - were located halfway into the living and bedroom, therefore only having half of their presence in the main rooms. This resulted in the main rooms feeling larger and more spacious. In addition to this, most of the flat was built by the client and so cheaper in the long run. The apartment's colour scheme was inspired by a traditional Armenian tile - Susan's choice - that had been used in the bathroom: there was white, ochre and deep blue.&#xD;It was a pleasure to work with clients who basically let me do the design work, as I understood how to best fit - functionally and aesthetically - their brief. The contractor would measure the design's success through its functionality and efficiency, though he reminded me often to contribute my architectural thinking to his brief. I had to rationalise my aesthetically-driven attitude through what was considered good in the client's mind: an efficient use of space. For example, by having the sofa built into a hole with only half of its width visible would save space and money, as he would not have to buy a new sofa. Of course, the aesthetic reason for installing these 'functional boxes' into the wall was no less important: the different heights made the wall feel lighter and look more interesting. The 'toilet box' was particularly successful: most people were taken by surprise to find an extra toilet in a public space. It was 'hanging' on the wall (by cantilever) and was not at all overt about its function.&#xD;The most frustrating aspect of this job was the fact that on site the work was being done in such a basic manner. We were not in a remote or poor place: we were in Tel-Aviv, a very dynamic city with a modern, sophisticated culture. I decided that on my next project I would look for an alternative way of realising my plans with the minimum involvement of unskilled work on site, and I felt lucky that the conditions of the next project allowed me to fulfil that ambition.&#xD;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="25_Dadush_Residence,_Tel_Aviv,_1993_-_1994_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="572px" height="72px"/>
</content>
